Most people believe that
while selecting medical insurance, the
most important thing is to look at the premium.
But the real story begins when
someone faces a medical emergency.  Then the claim
settlement ratio, waiting period,
eligibility criteria, coverage and optional
benefits decide how much your policy will
protect you.  In today's video,
we will compare the top six medical insurance
plans and understand what
you should consider before finalizing a policy.
Before starting the video, let me introduce myself.  I
am Soni Chauhan and welcome to Policy
Hub.  Where we make insurance
easy to understand.  If you have
any confusion related to insurance then
book your free consultation now
with our IRDAI certified advisors and get
all your confusions cleared.  The link
is given in the description below.
You can also follow us on our other social media
platforms to
get the latest updates related to insurance.  Today's video is going to be very
important.  So do
n't skip the video at all, stay till the end.
Because by the end you will understand exactly
what is important while selecting a right medical insurance plan.
So let us first talk about
an important factor.  That is
claim settlement ratio.  This number indicates
how efficiently a company
settles claims.  The six
insurers we will be talking about today are HDFC Ago,
Tata AIG, Bajaj Alanj, ICICI LBA NE BPA
and Care Health Insurance.  In this,
CSR of HDFC Ago is 99%, Tata AIG 95%, Bajaj Allians
96%, ICICI LBD 97%, Neema BPA and Care Health
92%.  Overall, all insurers have maintained a
healthy and trustworthy claims record
which is
a strong and positive sign for policy holders.  Now let's talk about
their eligibility criteria.
Who can be covered?  What are the age limits
and how much flexibility is available in including family members.
Adult entry age in HDSC Airgo Optimus Secure is
18 years to maximum with no age limit.
That means this plan
is also available for senior citizens.  and Dependent Child 91
Days to 25 Years.
Adult entry age in Tata AIG Medic Select is 18 years to
maximum no age limit and dependent
child zero days to 25 years which is
ideal for new borns.
Adult entry age in Bajaj Aanj My Health Care Plan is
18 years to 65 years.  Dependent Child
91 Days to 30 Years.
Adult entry age in ICICI Low LMB Elevate plan is 18 years to
maximum with no age limit.  Dependent Child
91 Days to 30 Years.  In Neema Bhupa Reassure
3.0, adult entry age is 18 years to 99
years, dependent child is 91 days to 30
years and in Care Health Ultimate Care Plan,
adult entry age is 18 years to maximum
no age limit and dependent child is 91 days
to 24 years can be covered in floater plan.
If we talk about the maximum policy
tenure and sum insured, then in HDFC Ergo
Optima Secure the policy tenure is
maximum 3 years and sum insured option is Rs 5 lakh
to Rs 2 crore.  In Tata AIG Medicate Select
Plan, policy term in your maximum 3 years
sum insured option is Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 crore.
In Bajaj Ayaz, policy term in your maximum 3 years
and sum insured option is Rs 5 lakh to Rs 5 crore.
In ICICI Lo LMB Elevate Plan, maximum
policy term in your 5 years sum insured option is Rs
5 lakh to unlimited sum insured. In Neema Bhupa
Reshore 3.0, policy term in your 3 years and
sum insured option is unlimited.
In Care Health Ultimate Care Plan, policy term
in your maximum 5 years and sum insured
option is Rs 5 lakh to Rs 1 crore is available.
Talking about the base features, there is no limit on
room rent and ICU charges in HDFCO Optima Secure.
Free and post
hospitalization 60 days and 180 days AYUSH
treatment is also included and a bonus of 50% of sum
insured is available every year which
increases up to a maximum of 100% and
this bonus is not reduced on claim.  There
is no limit on single private AC room and ICU charges in Tata AIG Medicare Select plan.  Pre
and post hospitalization is 90 and 90 days.
AYUSH treatment is included and
up to 100% bonus is available.  There is no limit on
room rent and ICU charges in Bajaj Allianz My Healthcare Plan.
Free
forced hospitalization 60 days and 90 days
AYUSH treatment is included and bonus up
to 100% is available.  Talking about ICIC Lombard Elevate
Plan, it includes single private AC
room, pre-enforced hospitalization 90 days
and 180 days.  AYUSH treatment is included
and an annual bonus of 20% of the sum insured is
given, maximum up to 100%.  There is no limit on
room and ICU charges under the Neema Reshore 3.0 plan.
Pre &
Post Hospitalization 60 Days & 180 Days
and IUSH Treatment is fully included.
Whereas in Care Health Ultimate Care Plan,
room rent and ICU charges are fully covered.
Pre & Post Hospitalization 60 Days
& 90 Days, AYUSH Treatment is fully covered
and No Claim Bonus is available maximum up
to 100%.  Now let's move on to their unique features
which make each plan different from the other.
Features like Secure Benefit, Plus Benefit, Restoration Benefit and Protect Benefit within HDFCO Optima Secure automatically help enhance your sum at
no
extra cost.  Tata AIG Medi Care
Select plan
focuses on affordability and practicality with
options like unlimited restore benefit, inflation protection, consumables covers, infinite advantage and maternity care.
Talking about Bajaj Aayaz My Healthcare Plan, it includes OPD coverage,
doctor consultation, medicines and maternity
benefits which is
beneficial for young couples.  Features like
Worldwide Cover, Chronic Disease
Management, Newborn Cover, BeFit Benefit
and Power Booster are available in ICIC LBD Elevate.
Niva Rear Shot 3.0 comes with strong unique benefits like Wellness Rewards,
Day One PED Cover, Lock the Clock Benefit,
Well Consult Plus and Global Cover.
Benefits like instant cover, unlimited recharge, premium payback, wellness discount and infinity bonus
are available under the Care Health Ultimate Care Plan.  Who focus more on preventive health care.
Now let's talk about the discounts on these plans
which make the policy pocket
friendly.
Loyalty discount of 2.5%,
family discount of 10% and long term
discount up to 10% are available under HDFCO Optima Secure.
Long term
discount up to 7.5%, family floater
discount up to 32%, professional discount
7.5% and young family discount 10%
are available under Tata AJ Medicash Select plan.  Under Bajaj Allianz My Healthcare
Plan, zone discount up to 25%,
family discount 10%, long term
discount up to 8%, loyalty discount 5%
and wellness discount up to 10%
are available.  ICICI Low LBD offers credit score
discount up to 15%, wellness discount up
to 30%, early renewal discount 2.5% and
long term discount up to 15%.
Live health
discount up to 30%, family discount 10%
and long term discount up to 15%
are available at Neeva Reshore 3.0.  Whereas, under Care Health Ultimate
Care Plan, wellness discount up
to 30% is available.  Now according to me, the best way to
select a safe health insurance
is to focus on three things.
Reliability, coverage and flexibility.
Plans like HDFC Ergo Optimus Secure and ICIC LBD Elevate offer
strong performance in terms of claim settlement ratio and coverage.
If you want comprehensive plans like maternity coverage, OPD,
critical illness, wellness and global cover,
then ICICI
LBD Elevate NIV bua rehsur 3.0 and Bajaj
Alanaj My Health Care Plan are great choices.
If you need long-term savings or family
support, HDFC Ergo Optima
Secure, Tata AIG Meic Select and CareHealth
Ultimate Care
offer extra value.  The right end of the day plan is the one
that matches your budget
without compromising on your complete
protection.  Every family's needs are different.
Whether you
need insurance for parents, OPD coverage, dental
coverage or unlimited sum insurance.  If
you want to know more about these plans, then
you can watch the complete review of these plans
on the end screen of the video.
If you are still confused about which
plan will be best for you, you can
book a free consultation with our experts.  The
link is given in the description below.
If you found this video helpful,
please like, share and subscribe to the channel.  See you
in the next video with another infatuation topic.
Till then stay safe, stay in the Shard.